SUNIL SUCKOO

ssuckoo16@gmail.com http://sunilsuckoo.github.io/ 734-255-5138

Education

2016 Amherst College (3.74 GPA)

Anthropology

Magna Cum Laude Honors

2015 Danish Institute for Study Abroad

Gender Studies

Employment

Contact Design, Inc.

Seattle, WA Jan 2017 to Present

User Researcher

- Vet 1,000+ research participants (job verification/criminal background checks).
- Schedule and conduct 10+ field studies (home visits, sightseeing, etc.) per week that centered on everyday activities.
- Prepare and debrief participants (families, children, etc.) in accordance with the legal, client, and GfK guidelines provided.

Wunderman Planning/Strategy Intern Seattle, WA Oct 2016 to Present

- Introduce UX and other formal research methods to Planning/Strategy team.
- Plan ongoing mixed-method research projects on Microsoft and T-Mobile users.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams (creatives, copywriters, etc.) to create multi-channel advertisements.

Amherst College Resident Counselor (RC) Department of Student Life Aug 2014 to May 2016

- Planned 20+ events with nearly perfect attendance (20-25 students) using survey and ethnographic data.
- Co-founded the RC Council, which successfully advocated a +30% salary and +150% yearly budget.

University of Chicago

Chicago, IL Jun 2014 to Aug 2014

Mellon Initiative Research Fellow

- Conducted qualitative research (ethnography, field studies, interviews, card sorting) on diversity in higher education.
- Presented at Leadership Alliance National Symposium (350+ undergraduates, 50 grad students, 25 scholars) and UChicago Research Symposium (20+ scholars).
- Proposed 10 new paid diversity center staff positions to Amherst College.

Projects

Product Evangelism (GiveSafe)

Feb 2017 to Present

• Recruit 40+ users for GiveSafe, a nonprofit enabling users to donate directly to homeless individuals via credit/debit card.

Millennial Cyborgs (Senior Thesis)

Aug 2015 to May 2016

- Wrote 110-page thesis on American millennials' technology use, based on 5+ years of ethnography, field studies, diary studies, interviews, and 140+ survey responses.
- Presented to 50+ students, 20+ doctoral scholars, and 10+ business professionals at the Five College Anthropology Conference.

Summary

- User researcher with a focus on millennials.
- Record of implementing effective change.
- Interests: Random Acts of Kindness, Independent Films, Writing (Fantasy and Sci-Fi), and Flamin' Hot®.

Skills

Ethnography, Interviewing, Survey Design, Field Studies, Contextual Inquiry, Focus Groups, Usability Testing, Affinity Diagram, Presentation

Awards

Donald S. Pitkin Prize 2016 Amherst College Anthropology-Sociology Department

\$400 to best Anthropology-Sociology thesis out of 12 honors theses.

Watson Fellowship Finalist 2016

6% admission rate, 4 students selected on strength of research proposal, personal statement, and interview.

Gregory S. Call Fellow Dean of Students

Awarded \$4,280 summer living stipend and full funding (\$1,500+) for B.A. thesis.

Wilfred D. Webb Award Hazel Park High School

The valedictorian with the strongest commitment to community service.

Mathematics Award Hazel Park High School

\$25 to most promising AP Calculus student out of 20 students.

Writing Award Hazel Park High School

\$25 to AP English student with the best writing skills out of 25 students.

2012

2012

2015

2012